# JUSTIN LATTIMORE

## SUMMARY

[WILLING TO RELOCATE] As a product-oriented individual, I focus on getting results first. I'm a Web Developer with a background as a Digital Artist (3D and 2D) thus granting me strong Graphic Design skills. I have an unconventional entry into this industry because I knew that developing applications for the web is what I wanted to do after meeting some engineers at a Unity Meetup. I bring a youthful growth mindset and eagerness to use new skills and technologies. My experience as an artist has helped me to be a creative problem solver! Feel free to check out my projects on my site or Github.

## **PROJECTS**

#### **Responsive Site for BarnesKing Tire**

Website for a local business that is responsive and works well on both desktop and mobile devices. Uses media queries for responsiveness.

#### Fortress Defenders

Creation and modification API for a card game. Built with MongoDB, Express, React, NodeJS. Built for a less tech-savvy Game Designer to be able to modify the API to a card game for game-play purposes so that Unreal and/or Unity could make HTTP request and populate a session with card data.

#### Crypto-Central

ReactJS app that incorporates coinmarketcap.com's API to display data that can be sorted. A Firebase-powered chat feature checks for User's presence. via Firebase Authentication.

#### Mockpons

Pong game made with HTML5 <canvas>. Simulated AI works off of the location of the ball and repositions at a speed limit in order to bounce it back at the player.

#### PSD-to-HTML-1

Assessment made from a PSD. (PSD to HTML exercise)

#### Mockipedia

A Ruby on Rails Wikipedia-ish app. CRUD practice with which I implemented Devise for Users, Redcarpet for Markdown and Pundit for a user experience and authorization in order to create, edit and destroy Wikis.

# **EMPLOYMENT**

#### BarnesKing Tire Contract Web Developer Spindale, NC Dec. 2018 to Jan. 2019

Designed a website for a local business that is responsive and works well on both desktop and mobile devices. Uses media queries for responsiveness. Set up google maps for multiple locations. HTML5, CSS3, ES6.

#### RockAgile.io · Contract Web Developer · Charlotte, NC · Jan. 2018 to July 2018

Front End programming, Ruby on Rails, debugging. I completed tickets for an app called Infinity ERP that Rock Agile migrated from Rails 2.3 to Rails 5.0!

## Vizitech USA · 3D Environment Artist · Atlanta, GA · Aug. 2014 to Jan. 2015

3D modeling and texturing for the <u>Flexible Pavement Inspection Program</u> that would train GDOT (Georgia Department of Transportation) inspectors for real-world locations in downtown Atlanta, GA.

#### Fabrication Laboratory (Fab Lab) Contract 3D Modeling Rutherfordton, NC Nov. 2013 to Feb. 2014

3D modeling, 3D printing, Graphic Design, Photoshop and GIMP for Fab Lab's clients. Carried out the production of products with a MakerBot Replicator to meet customers' needs. Also operated a laser engraver for on-demand solutions.

### Foothills Connect · Senior Director's Assistant · Rutherfordton, NC · Sept. 2006 to Aug. 2007

Database, Spreadsheets, Graphic Design for Logos, Flyers, Postcards. Worked as a consultant for customers who wanted business cards and brochures as well as directly assisting the Senior Director with data entry.

#### Skewed Perceptions · 2D Artist · Atlanta, GA · Feb. 2013 to Apr. 2013

Contract Photoshop Alteration, Colorist for Comic Book. Implemented improvements from page to page on "<u>"Lightners Strike!"</u>" in order to enhance and correct errors behind previous artist.

#### Dermaglove (Contract) · Video Digital Marketing · Atlanta, GA · Mar. 2018 to May 2018

Produced a commercial for Shopify based web site. Created from After Effects CS5 in full HD and animated frame-by-frame effects in Flash CS5 for the full composition.

# OTHER EXPERIENCE

#### **USIC (United States Infrastructure Corporation)**

Asheville, NC · June 2015 to Oct. 2016

Locate Technician for optical fiber and copper communication lines, Duke/Progress Energy assets, Piedmont Gas lines. Forced me to develop communication skills in order to coordinate with excavators so that we could eliminate as much damage to underground infrastructure as possible. Executed tickets in all conditions to complete task that made a lot people quit just from the training which helped me develop grit.

## SKILLS

#### WEB DEVELOPMENT

HTML5

CSS3

React.is

JavaScript ES6

Ruby 2.5.3

Rails 5.0

Active Record

jQuery2.2.4

Bootstrap V3.3.7

SASS

Angular1

#### **DIGITAL ARTIST**

Maya 3D

Zbrush

After Effects

Photoshop

Illustrator

**Ouixel Suite** 

Topogun

headus UVLayout

# **EDUCATION**

#### Bloc

Full Stack Web Developer Apprenticeship (2016 2017)

Art Institute of Atlanta BFA - Game Art and Design (2007 - 2011)

# CONTACT

**■** ilattimoreweb@gmail.com

jlattimore.com

**4** (678) 684-8495

in /in/justin-lattimore-

90387445/

Wyzardsleeves